PAUL KUZMA

317.407.5789 I kuzma.paul@gmail.com I www.linkedin.com/in/pkuzma101 I https://github.com/pkuzma101

WEB DEVELOPER I Professional Coder

I love the process of building web software and pages and am eager to bring my passion to an organization that needs a highly motivated web developer who can quickly learn new technologies. After working as a part-time PHP Developer, I was hired as a full-time Front End Developer for Main Street Power Mail, where I make a dynamic front end experience. Prior to becoming a developer, I spent seven years as a professional educator, where I developed strong record-keeping, customer service, and interpersonal skills.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATION

CodeUp - a 12-week, intensive web development boot camp in 2014 Taylor University - B.S. in Elementary Education, 2006

TECH-STACK

PHP MySQL JavaScript (with a focus on jQuery) Laravel (Ruby on) Rails WordPress HTML5 CSS3 AngularJs Bootstrap

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Main Street Power Mail CMA, Indianapolis, IN

July 2015 - February 2016

track.mspowermail.com

I used jQuery and JavaScript to create all pages on the company CMA dynamically using AJAX. I also created an interactive calendar on which users could make and edit their appointments, and have all their appointments tracked on one page. In addition, I created a network of forms sorted in different tabs and separated by an accordion for the page on which agents could run a count of leads in a particular area. Bootstrap was used for modal functionality, and dynamic resizability was achieved through my own custom media queries.

Front End Developer

Front end developer for a Carmel, Indiana-based company that finds leads for insurance salesmen. I create a dynamic, elegant front end through extensive use of JavaScript and jQuery. In addition, I also do back end work with MySQL through the use of Ruby on Rails, where I have become proficient in both stored procedures and the Rails 'Active Record' framework.

End Result, Indianapolis, IN March 2015 - July 2015 PHP Developer

PHP Developer for a company that records times and performance for races. Built an online calendar on which users may post events and link to register for them. Was responsible for both front end and back end work, ranging the entire CRUD spectrum.

Codeup, San Antonio, TX September 2014 - February 2015 Freelance Developer I attended a web development boot camp where I learned the full LAMP Stack in addition to JavaScript, jQuery, Git, and MySQL. I helped to develop World Mentor, a Laravel-based site where entrepreneurs around the world could give and receive mentoring advice. I also created a whack-a-mole game using JavaScript and jQuery and a digital things-to-do list using PHP and MySQL.

Projects

WorldMentr.org - https://github.com/worldmentr/capstone

I was the lead front end developer for a Laravel-based website that would allow entrepreneurs around the world to give and receive mentoring advice across the web. Bootstrap was used extensively for dynamic resizability and page layout.

Final Fantasy Database - http://paulkuzmadev.com/projects/final_fantasy/characters.php

This app makes use of PHP and MySQL to allow users to create information cards about characters from the popular video game series. I used CSS3 and HTML5 to create a look reminiscent of the games of the mid-90's, and Bootstrap provides media queries and modal functionality, as well as the grid system used in the creation of the character cards.

Synonym Matching - http://paulkuzmadev.com/projects/synonym/synonym.php

This jQuery-based app is a digitized version of a grammar game I created as a teacher. 15 pairs of matching synonym cards are randomly arrayed on a grid structure, and each turn the player clicks on two cards, which remain face-up if their definitions match, earning the player a point. If cards do not match, the app is designed to keep the two cards visible for three seconds, giving the player time to memorize their locations.

Bakery - https://github.com/pkuzma101/blog.dev/tree/master/public/projects/bakery

This app uses AngularJS to create an online bake shop where users can purchase different foods and see their bill calculated in real time. Both Bootstrap and my own custom media queries are used to create dynamic resizability.

Pet All Puppies - http://paulkuzmadev.com/projects/whackamole/puppy.html

This app uses jQuery and JavaScript to create a whack-a-mole game that keeps track of how many puppies the player has successfully clicked in the 3 seconds they appeared onscreen.

AJAX Address Book - http://paulkuzmadev.com/projects/address/address book.php

This app uses AJAX and jQuery to create an address book that updates in real time all entries that are fed to it. The entire CRUD spectrum is utilized.

WordPress site - https://github.com/pkuzma101/test2.dev/tree/master/public

I created a website for a Chicago-area graphic artist using WordPress. I found a theme appropriate for his needs, and created or adjusted page templates to create a site that would be easy to maintain and upgrade for a person not knowledgeable in web development.

Professional Educator 2007 to 2014

I taught all grades 2-9 at four different schools over a period of seven years, and practiced web development in my spare time during the last of these years. I tailored my instruction to fit the needs of my students, which at one school were exclusively special needs children. I developed strong relations with students and their families, and kept detailed and organized records of student progress.